Saurabh Pawar

IICS Developer

💌 saurabhpawar6607@gmail.com 📞 +918691989830 💡 Pune, India

Profile

I am urgently looking for a better opportunity as a IICS Developer. Having 1.8 years of experience with knowledge of technologies like IICS, Big Query, GCP, Informatica PowerCenter, MySQL, Unix, Teradata, Jira, Control-M, Bitbucket and Bamboo.

Skills

Languages

SQL, UNIX/Shell Scripting, Python (Basics)

Databases

Google Big Query, Teradata, Microsoft SQL Server, Oracle

Tools

IICS, GCP, Teradata, Putty, Informatica PowerCenter, SSMS, Jira, Bamboo, Bitbucket, Control-M

Personal Strengths

- Ability to cope up with different situations, selfmotivated.
- Good analytical and problem-solving skills
- Excellent data analysis and data profiling skills using Informatica and Excel.
- Result Oriented and self-starter who enjoys a challenge and needs.
- Good written and verbal communication skills, mastery in English and local language

Awards and Honors

 Received accolades from project manager for consistent performance and demonstrated a proactive "can-do" attitude in delivering exceptional results on projects.

Education

B.E. in IT Engineering, Savitribai Phule Pune University,

06/2018 - 06/2021 | Pune, India

Diploma in IT Engineering, BATU University,

06/2015 - 06/2018 | Raigad, India

Professional Experiences

Mphasis, IICS Developer 10/2021 - present | Pune, India

Project: DaRT-GDT Managed Capacity (Banking Domain)

Role: IICS Developer.
Client: Charles Schwab

Duration: Oct 2021 to Till Date

The Charles Schwab Corporation provides a full range of brokerage, banking and financial advisory services through its operating subsidiaries.

Role and Responsibilities:

- Designing and developing data integration workflows using Informatica Intelligent Cloud Services (IICS) to extract, transform, and load data from various sources.
- Made necessary modifications to the source query in Big Query after conducting testing, ensuring the query aligns with the desired data extraction and meets the project requirements in IICS.
- As an IICS Developer responsible for monitoring and maintaining the health of data integration processes, I ensured that scheduled jobs ran successfully and that data was processed efficiently.
- Created IICS Connections using various cloud Connectors in IICS Administrator.
- Successfully created a secure agent in IICS (Informatica Intelligent Cloud Services) to establish a secure connection and enable secure data integration and processing between on-premises systems and cloud-based applications.
- Created a parameter file in Unix and successfully utilized it in IICS for configuring and managing runtime parameters in data integration workflows.
- Successfully deployed IICS task flows using Bamboo tool for seamless integration and automation.
- Implemented data synchronization processes to ensure realtime and accurate data across multiple systems in our project using DMU tool.
- Utilized the MDCert tool to perform comprehensive data validation in our project
- Responsible for the successful deployment of task flow in production, ensuring seamless integration and adherence to quality standards.
- Created a Change Request (CRQ) and Incident in the Remedy system to document the production deployment of IICS, capturing relevant information and providing a record for tracking and managing the deployment process and any related incidents or issues.
- Worked with a team of 2 Onshore and 7 offshore Members of Team and prioritizing project tasks.

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the above information is furnished by me and is true to the best of my knowledge.